Guide to the Melville Cane Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, Christchurch, N.Z., 7 Sept 1968, (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, New Haven, CT, 31 Oct 1968, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, n.p., 25 Dec 1968, (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, New Haven, CT, 16 June 1969, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, New Haven, CT, 2 July 1971, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes To Melville Cane, [New Haven, CT], ca. 9 Dec 1974, (2 pages a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 5)
  - Pease, Henrietta F. (Mrs. Arthur S.) To Melville Cane, Randolph, NH, 13 July 1945, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Oct 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 12 Nov 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Nov 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 12 Jan 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 18 Feb 1939, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 1 March 1939, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 8 March 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 6 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 20 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 22 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 28 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 9 May 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 10 May 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 11 May 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 31 May 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 2 June 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 13 June 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 22 June 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With copy of related memo]
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Pincus Berner, New York, 28 July 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Pincus Berner, New York, 6 Sept 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 20 Sept 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 12 Dec 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 10 Jan 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 26 Jan 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 30 Jan 1940, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 17 Feb 1940, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Feb 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Pincus Berner, New York, 23 March 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 2 Dec 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 12 March 1941, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 25 Sept 1941, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 30 Nov 1942, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 4 Feb 1943, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Dec 1943, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 20 Sept 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Nov 1945, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Pincus Berner, New York, 4 March 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell E. To Melville Cane, New York, 8 April 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Rand, Ayn To Melville Cane, n.p., 15 Feb 1936, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ransom, John Crowe To Melville Cane, Gambier, OH, 25 March 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ransom, John Crowe To Melville Cane, Gambier, OH, 20 Nov 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ransom, John Crowe To Melville Cane, Gambier, OH, 17 March 1944, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ransom, John Crowe To Melville Cane, Gambier, OH, 10 Dec 1946, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., n.d., (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 30 Jan n.y., (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., 13 Aug n.y., (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 24 Sept 1925, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 8 Oct 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, [ca. 1926], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 18 March 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 24 March 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 8 Dec 1933, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 23 Feb 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, [New York?], 24 March 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 20 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 30 June 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 12 June 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 7 Oct 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 8 Dec 1942, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 23 Feb 1942, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 2 Jan 1943, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, [New York], [Feb 1943], (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [Written on a realted letter & with copies of 2 related letters]
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 8 Feb 1943, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 13 April 1943, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Florence Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 1944, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, [1944], (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Pleasantville, NY, 1 Nov 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 16 Feb 1945, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 27 Feb 1946, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 1 April 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 11 April 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 5 June 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Woodstock, NY, 21 June 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., [25 Dec 1950], (1 a.n.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., 15 Dec 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., 14 April 1953, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 14 May 1953, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 31 Aug 1956, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 4 Nov 1957, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 18 Dec 1957, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 22 Sept 1958, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, n.p., 30 Sept 1958, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 16 Feb 1959, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, Tenafly, NJ, 6 April 1959, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 13 April 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton To Melville Cane, New York, 13 April 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Rodgers, Richard To Melville Cane, New York, 7 Jan 1952, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ross, Harold W. To Melville Cane, New York, 6 Sept 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ross, Harold W. To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Dec 1939, (1 page t.l.s., 1 ms.n. (by Cane; on same page)) (Box 5)
    [In reply to: [Cane, Melville]. To The New Yorker, 19 Dec 1939.]
  - Rukeyser, Muriel To Melville Cane, New York, 18 April 1950, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel To Melville Cane, n.p., 2 Oct 1968, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel To Melville Cane, New York, 29 Oct 1968, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Sandburg, Carl To Melville Cane, Flat Rock, NC, 16 Nov 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sandburg, Carl To Melville Cane, Flat Rock, NC, 18 Sept 1959, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Saroyan, Aram To Melville Cane, [New York], 17 May 1963, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Saroyan, William To Melville Cane, n.p., 27 Sept 1956, (1 a.n.s.) (Box 6)
  - Saroyan, William To Melville Cane, New York, 13 Sept 1962, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Saroyan, William To Melville Cane, Atlantic Ocean, 18 Oct 1963, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Saroyan, William To Melville Cane, Paris, 30 Nov 1963, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Schorer, Mark To Melville Cane, Berkeley, CA, 14 Dec 1972, (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery To Melville Cane, New York, 22 July 1904, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery To Melville Cane, New York, 29 July 1904, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery To Melville Cane, New York, 26 Aug 1904, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Shapiro, Karl To Melville Cane, Lincoln, NE, 26 Feb 1957, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Shapiro, Karl To Melville Cane, Lincoln, NE, 16 Oct 1959, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Mary Craig Kimbrough (Mrs. Upton) To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 20 May 1955, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Pasadena, CA, 25 Jan 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Pasadena, CA, 7 Dec 1942, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 12 May 1945, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 16 Jan 1948, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, March 1953, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 21 April [1953], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 19 April 1953, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 7 May 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, n.p., 16 Feb 1961, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 7 Oct 1961, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton To Melville Cane, Monrovia, CA, 7 July 1964, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Speyer, Leonora To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Feb n.y., (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Speyer, Leonora To Melville Cane, New York, 9 Dec 1937, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Speyer, Leonora To Melville Cane, New York, 25 Feb [1951], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Speyer, Leonora To Melville Cane, New York, 22 Jan 1955, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 8 July 1924, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 26 July 1924, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 24 Jan 1925, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Jan 1925, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 4 Feb 1925, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 3 April 1926, (3 pages a.l.s. (s. with initials)) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, New York, 1927, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, London, 2 June 1927, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Spingarn, Joel E. To Melville Cane, Tisbury, England, 17 Oct 1971, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred To Melville Cane, [New York], 31 Jan 1926, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Stout, Rex To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Feb 1975`, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, n.p., n.d., (1 a.n.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, New York, n.d., (1 Christmas card, s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, New York, 30 Oct 1942, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, Los Angeles, 2 July 1943, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, Los Angeles, 14 Aug 1943, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, Los Angeles, 27 Nov 1943, (8 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, n.p., 15 May 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, New York, 21 June 1948, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, Stockbridge, MA, 25 April 1949, (4 pages t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To Melville Cane, Stockbridge, MA, 20 May 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Struther, Jan To [Melville Cane], New York, 9 Nov 1952, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Tate, Allen To Melville Cane, Sewanee, TN, 7 July 1944, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Tate, Allen To Melville Cane, Sewanee, TN, 3 April 1945, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Tate, Allen To Melville Cane, New York, 11 Oct 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Thurber, James To Melville Cane, New York, 26 Sept 1960, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel To Melville Cane, Greens Farms, CT, 13, 21 July 1950, (1 a.p.c.s., 1 t.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Dec 1958, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel To Melville Cane, New York, 23 May 1966, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel To Melville Cane, New York, 10 June 1968, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel To Melville Cane, New York, 29 Feb 1972, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Margaret Terry Chanler (Mrs. Winthrop A.), Cobham, VA, 15 Feb 1935, (3 pages a.l.s. (with envelope)) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Melville Cane, Cobham, VA, 18 June 1938, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Melville Cane, Cobham, VA, 27 June 1938, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Melville Cane, Cobham, VA, 22 July 1938, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Melville Cane, Cobham, VA, 12 Jan 1939, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amelie Rives (Princess Pierre) To Melville Cane, Cobham, VA, 8 Nov 1939, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, New York, 13 Nov 1929, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Elizabethtown, NY, 27 June 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Elizabethtown, NY, 2 July 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Elizabethtown, NY, 10 July 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Erie, PA, 11 Nov 1936, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, New York, 12 July 1946, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Brooklyn, NY, [1947], (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, New York, 18 April 1949, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Brooklyn, NY, 3 April 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis To Melville Cane, Newtown, CT, 5 Feb 1958, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Irita To Melville Cane, New York, 18 Sept 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Irita To Melville Cane, New York, 24 May 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Irita To Melville Cane, New York, 29 Sept 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 9 May 1940, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, New York, 16 Feb 1956, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Feb 1956, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 4 Jan 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 22 Feb 1963, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 21 March 1967, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 30 March 1968, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 23 June 1969, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark To Melville Cane, Falls Village, CT, 9 April 1971, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Viereck, Peter To Melville Cane, South Hadley, MA, 14 June 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Viereck, Peter To Melville Cane, South Hadley, MA, 3 July 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Viereck, Peter To Melville Cane, South Hadley, MA, 10 Feb 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison To Sullivan & Cromwell, New York, 15 June 1903, (1 page t.l.s. (recommending Cane)) (Box 6)
  - Wallace, Irving To Melville Cane, Los Angeles, 4 April 1971, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wallace, Irving To Melville Cane, Los Angeles, 23 Jne 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., n.d., (1 a.n.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., n.d., (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., n.d., (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Vallejo, CA, 20 Dec 1945, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 13 Jan 1946, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 14 Feb 1946, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 14 March 1946, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 12 April 1946, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 17 July 1946, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 27 Oct 1946, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 22 Jan 1947, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 22 April 1947, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 21 Feb 1948, (1 page t.l.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 11 April 1948, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 23 June 1952, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 15 July 1952, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 30 March 1954, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 14 July 1954, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., [Dec 1954], (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., [11 Nov 1955], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., [Dec 1957], (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., [Dec 1959], (1 page a.l.s. (on Christmas card)) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 28 March 1959, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 9 Oct 1960, (5 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 2 Aug 1964, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, [California], 13 Dec 1964, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 23 May 1966, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, n.p., 14 April 1969, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 4 Aug 1970, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [With copy of earlier letter]
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 6 Dec 1971, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Salisbury, UK, 12 April 1973, (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - West, Jessamyn To Melville Cane, Napa, CA, 13 June 1975, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 20 Dec 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 10 April 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Nov 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 13 Oct 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 1 Nov 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 18 May 1959, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 19 Jan 1960, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 4 Oct 1960, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 29 March 1968, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Melville Cane, New York, 3 Jan 1974, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [With copy of same letter]
  - Wilbur, Richard To Melville Cane, n.p., [Christmas n.y.], (1 page a.l.s. (written on a Christmas greeting card)) (Box 6)
  - Williams, Oscar To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Oct 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Winters, Yvor To Melville Cane, Palo Alto, CA, 9 June 1930, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wolfe, Humbert To James Wells, London, 23 Dec 1929, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wolfe, Thomas To Melville Cane, n.p., 1929, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wolfe, Thomas To Melville Cane, Montreux, 22 July 1930, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Wolfe, Thomas To Melville Cane, New York, 22 Jan 1938, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [Also t. copy (incomplete), and carbon of Cane's reply]
  - Wolfe, Thomas Correspondence re. his estate, n.p., 1938-1939, (3 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [See also cataloged letters from Maxwell E. Perkins]
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Cane, Melville "Two Stars", [New York?], [ca. 17 Oct 1930], (1 page a.ms.s. (poem; copy)) (Box 1)
    [For the above See: Cane, Melville. To Abraham Valentine Williams Jackson, [17 Oct 1930].]
  - Cane, Melville January Garden, New York, 1926, (33 pages page proof (poems, with autograph corrections, in slipcase)) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville Poems since 1964, v.p., 1964-1972, (86 pages a.ms.s. (notebook, 1 volume)) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville "Query", [New York], [Sept 1947], (1 page a.ms. (poem)) (Box 1)
    [Last 3 lines added by Sinclair Lewis and are in his hand]
  - Cane, Melville "Winter Night", n.p., [1898 or 1899], (1 page a.ms. (poem)) (Box 1)
    [With corrections by George Edward Woodberry; with related material]
  - Cane, Melville Citation for his service with Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., presented on his one hundredth birthday, [New York], 15 April 1979, (1 page ms.d.) (Box 1)
  - [Erskine, John] "Materials of Poetry", [New York?], n.d., (3 pages a.d.) (Box 1)
  - Frost, Robert "Departmental", [Amherst, MA], [2 Dec 1935], (3 pages a.d.s. (poem)) (Box 2)
  - Frost, Robert "Willful Homing", [Amherst, MA], [15 Nov 1937], (1 page a.d.s. (s. to Melville Cane)) (Box 2)